It was you, wasn't it?
You're the one…
who replied to me as Moonee.
It never even crossed my mind that…
that could happen to him.
Did you perhaps see that photo?
The photo of a woman sitting on a bench.
Yes.
Do you know her too?
We called her "Dylan."
She was a fellow club member.
Could you help me meet with her?
Sure, but it's been a while
since we last spoke.
I'll see if anyone is still in touch.
Thank you.
Why do you want to meet her?
I want to ask her something
about my brother.
I think she might know the answer.
It's a green light.
I'll get going, then. Take care.
Right. Take care.
I think it might be a first for her,
opening up to someone about that.
Hey.
Have you eaten?
I have.
I acted silly earlier, didn't I?
Something urgent came up.
I know it was because of your brother.
Sang-hak seonbae told me.
He said that he was with you just now.
Word travels fast.
It sure didn't take him long
to report back to you.
You're okay, right?
Of course I am.
I was doing you both a favor
by giving you some privacy.
You should be thanking me.
Don't you worry. We always make time
to enjoy each other's company.
I'm well aware.
He… seemed pretty shocked.
Yeah, he did.
It must have shocked you too.
Who would have thought
that he knew your brother?
Yeah, I was just as shocked.
I can't quite believe it either.
If you're hungry,
there's pizza on the dining table.
I told you I ate.
But thanks.
Good night.
YOU AND EVERYTHING ELSE
What I find so strange
is how, despite being so close,
you didn't know each other's names.
He never told us.
Everyone called each other
by their usernames,
but over time, we learned
each other's real names and schools.
But no one knew anything about Moonee
until the very end.
There is one person who may have known.
Anyway, that was just him.
That does sound like him,
considering his personality and all.
It's still so weird to think…
that he was also called Sang-hak.
What are the odds?
Do you want a Big Mac for lunch tomorrow?
Meaningful? How do you eat
a Big Mac meaningfully?
What?
How does that make it meaningful?
You're so silly.
We could go for two, maybe three burgers.
Let's go to Burger King right after.
Just in case you missed dinner. Enjoy.
Hi, Uncle Tat.
I am doing well.
We can't meet right now,
but I'm doing really well.
Hi…
Uncle Tat.
Hi, Uncle Tat.
You like Stephen Chow movies, don't you?
I really like his films too.
A CHINESE ODYSSEY
STARRING STEPHEN CHOW
A CHINESE ODYSSEY 2
- Hey, Sang-yeon.
- Hey.
Hello, seonbae.
No, I'm done with classes today.
Really?
These are the ones?
Yes. These are the tapes
in that photograph.
He lent them to me,
and I guess I'm finally returning them.
They star Stephen Chow.
Have you seen them?
No.
Give them a go. Your brother liked them.
They're really funny but also sad.
Did you know my username
comes from these movies?
I owe my friendship with your brother
to Stephen Chow.
It was the topic
of our very first conversation.
Hi, Uncle Tat.
You like Stephen Chow movies, don't you?
My username "Moonee" is the Korean name
of the actress Mo Wenwei.
Wait, Mo Wenwei?
And not Moonee, as in the moon?
No, not the moon, but Mo Wenwei.
He came up with it after seeing her
in A Chinese Odyssey.
I see.
As for Dylan's number, I've asked a guy
from the club who's well-connected.
Let's wait and see.
Thank you.
You don't need to thank me.
I'm just as curious about him as you are.
Still, thanks.
- Where's your boyfriend?
- I think he's with Sang-yeon.
Just the two of them?
Yeah, he needs to give her something.
Ryu Eun-jung, you're brimming
with confidence, aren't you?
What are you getting at?
Yeah, okay. You're not the jealous type.
Of course I am.
But if I stress over them having tea,
our relationship's as good as doomed.
I warn you not to be overly trusting.
You never know what might ignite a spark
between a man and a woman.
How did you know that I was Uncle Tat?
Sorry?
The fact that I was Uncle Tat.
You already knew, didn't you?
Isn't that why you didn't ask me yesterday
how I knew about the message from Moonee?
- You're right.
- How did you know?
I don't recall ever writing my real name
in my messages to him.
Maybe not in your messages,
but you must have written it somewhere.
I happened to log in
to my brother's messenger account,
and I saw that a user named Uncle Tat
was the only one truly concerned for him.
A whole year after his passing, at that.
So, out of curiosity,
I looked up all of your posts.
I must have seen your name,
Kim Sang-hak, then.
So you knew me from the start?
Even before you joined the club?
Yes.
Why didn't you say something
if you knew who I was?
If I had…
would anything be different?
What?
Of course things would be different.
You're Moonee's sister.
If I had known from the start,
I would have looked out for you more.
I don't need any of that.
I don't need you to look out for me.
Why not? It's always nice to know
that someone's got your back.
Thanks for these tapes.
Will you be staying?
Yeah. When Eun-jung gets here,
we're meeting the others--
I'll see you, then.
My bad.
It's fine. I'll pay for…
Sang-yeon's going on a blind date?
Yeah. Why do you look so shocked?
Of course it's shocking.
She's been indifferent to all guys.
When did she say she'd go on a blind date?
I ran into her earlier on campus.
I told her A-ra turned it down,
and she asked to go instead.
How strange.
What's up with her?
I'll also have a Big Mac.
- Two Big Mac combos, please.
- Sure.
Wait, this one's on me.
Since it's what you craved the most.
And extra ketchup, please.
Sure.
Do you think it's okay
if I don't text Sang-yeon?
About what?
That I'm not coming home.
What kind of person is Sang-yeon?
What kind of question is that?
You've known her for almost a year now.
What do you think?
I'm not sure.
She seems harder to read
than I first thought. More complex.
She is indeed hard to read and complex.
She has a tendency
to say and do the opposite.
The opposite?
I told you she puts on a front
when she's really struggling.
Maybe she's too proud.
- Complete opposite of me, isn't she?
- Totally.
An early start?
I have an early class.
So do I.
You're running late.
Hello.
Oh, hey. You must have a morning class.
Yes, first period.
Seonbae.
Did you tell Eun-jung
that I asked you for that girl's number?
No, I didn't. Why?
If you haven't,
could you please keep it a secret?
Why?
Just because it's my business.
I'd rather not discuss it with anyone
until I know what happened to my brother.
But, Sang-yeon… Eun-jung is curious
about your brother too.
I'll tell her eventually, once I find out.
You will?
I won't tell her, then.
Could you
also keep it a secret
that I sent messages to Uncle Tat?
How come?
You're still here?
Let's go. Yay, you're late too.
This is pretty good.
"Pretty good"? It's an A+!
What grade did you get last year?
An A… minus.
But it's really well-written.
So that's how you get an A+.
Really?
This is well-written?
All I did was talk crap about that film.
No, you were being honest
while providing a balanced argument.
I see why this is debate-worthy.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You know what? I really love movies.
I never knew that so much
could be captured in a single shot.
But it doesn't stop there.
In our last lecture,
we saw Fellini's I Vitelloni.
In the last scene, there's a tracking shot
of the friends asleep--
Hey, Ryu Eun-jung.
Yeah? What is it?
Pick one. Is it me or movies?
What?
Here you go.
What's this? Is this for me?
No way. It's a director's viewfinder!
Yeah, a mini one.
Do you like it?
I love it! How did you come up with
the idea to get me this?
You like taking pictures.
Since cameras aren't allowed on base,
I thought you could use this instead.
I'm so touched.
What is it?
I can't take this onto base.
Seriously? Why not?
We're only allowed watches.
Really?
Are you that bummed?
The military is so strict.
I was so excited to give you this.
Should I sneak it in?
What if you get caught?
I'd be in big trouble.
I'll make it up to you
by treasuring this for a long time. Deal?
Fine. Deal.
Are your dad's ancestral rites tonight?
Yeah, at midnight.
If you see Uncle Ddinguri later,
remind him about the loader.
Okay.
- I'm off.
- Bye.
Sang-yeon said it was as if by magic.
It was as if by magic…
Sang-hak seonbae happened to be there.
Sang-yeon.
What are you doing here?
I was going to look for some books.
- I see.
- What about you?
I was in Ilyeong to see Eun-jung.
Now I'm meeting someone here.
That's right.
They're doing their ancestral rites today.
Yeah.
You're headed back to base tomorrow,
aren't you?
Take care on your way back.
Yeah, have fun browsing for books.
Okay.
Sang-yeon, wait.
I'm actually meeting the guy
who may have Dylan's contact details.
Do you want to come with me?
Right now?
That, she said,
was how it had all started.
That unforgettable night.
JANG'S GAMJATANG
I'm sorry I couldn't find
Dylan's contact information.
Oh, don't be. I appreciate that
you took the time to look into it.
That doesn't mean I'm done looking.
I'll keep asking around.
Why are you looking for Dylan?
There's just something
I'd like to know about my brother.
What was he like? My brother.
Moonee?
Moonee was…
He was so meticulous.
I'm already laughing.
We'd be halfway through our meals,
and he'd still be mixing his food.
Man, he's so frustrating!
He was fine though.
We were the frustrated ones.
And he looks frail at first glance--
But, nope, that is one thing he's not.
Do you remember
his "you have no right" speech?
Heck yeah, I do. We were in Incheon,
and Moonee was so pissed.
- He marches right up to him--
- And says, "What are you doing, sir?"
- That sounds like him.
- "Sir, stop."
- Careful on your way home. Call me.
- Yeah, call me.
Call me.
I should have some of his photos at home.
Would you like them?
Yes, please.
I'll take anything of my brother's.
Is that so?
What's so funny?
Nothing. I just think Moonee
would have found you adorable just now.
My brother?
Did he ever mention me to you?
Mention you?
Yeah.
Forget I even asked.
You need to take the 134, right?
Yes.
Aren't you taking the subway?
We already passed the station.
I'll see you off.
I'm feeling a bit stuffy,
so I think I'll walk for a bit.
How about we walk to Jonggak station?
It would help us sober up.
I'd love to.
When he was younger,
he was a real chatterbox.
He used to play dollhouse with me
and was even nice enough
to let me hang out with his friends.
Then puberty hit,
and his personality changed.
I never understood it.
He became a different person overnight.
I think I have been upset with him
ever since.
Whenever we would get a chance to talk,
I was snappy for no particular reason.
Just like in his photo.
That's right. The "do not enter" sign.
Hang on.
He did mention you.
Aren't you good at dancing?
That's right. He did mention you.
He said you were a good dancer.
But he wouldn't even know.
My brother's never seen me dance before.
- He hasn't?
- Nope.
He bragged about how good you were,
and then he smiled, looking all pleased.
- He did?
- Yeah.
Now that I think about it,
that photo he took
of the "do not enter" sign…
maybe he actually wanted to enter.
Why else would he have taken that?
Every photo he took of you
showed his brotherly affection.
You think?
I can't believe I still remember all this.
What were you saying just now?
Watch the movie, and you'll get it.
Stephen Chow says these lines twice,
and the second time really hits home.
So are they sad lines?
You could say that.
It's still surprising that my brother
liked Stephen Chow movies.
I think he most liked A Chinese Odyssey.
Especially Part Two: Cinderella.
We're here.
Should we walk to the next station
so we can finish this conversation?
Shall we?
Part two is, in a way,
a prequel to the first movie.
The troubled Sun Wukong
finally realizes his destiny, and…
CHUNGJEONGNO STATION
We're here.
So we are.
I was so into our conversation
that I didn't even realize it.
Are your legs okay?
Hey, don't underestimate the ROK army.
Shouldn't you go now
if you want to catch the last train?
I'll walk you home since we're so close.
That'll at least give me bragging rights.
If you say so.
I want to know what you think
if you watch the films. Let me know.
I will.
By the way,
about those VHS tapes…
my brother didn't lend them to you.
What do you mean?
He gave them to you to keep.
The day he gave you those
was the day you last saw him, right?
He gave them to you for a reason.
He wanted you to have them.
Really?
Yes.
Did you know
that he gave Eun-jung his camera?
His camera?
It's the Leica I'm using now.
That roll of film
was loaded in the camera he gave her
before he left.
That was his will.
I knew it the moment I saw the photos.
"This is Cheon Sang-hak's will."
Isn't it exactly the sort of will
he'd leave behind?
I didn't even get a goodbye,
but he left Eun-jung his camera.
That's why I asked you not to tell her.
To keep it a secret from Eun-jung.
I wanted to find out first.
I wanted to be the one
who was the first to know.
Those tapes are yours,
so let's just say
I borrowed them from Uncle Tat for now.
Thank you for today.
No problem. I had fun too.
Good night.
Take care.
Okay.
Good night.
I liked Uncle Tat, you know.
You can't.
What do you mean I can't?
I said nothing about liking you.
I liked Uncle Tat, not Kim Sang-hak.
Right.
I'm grateful.
I never imagined that anyone
could care for a reckless fool like him.
I'm the one who's grateful.
If it weren't for Uncle Tat,
I would still be cooped up
in that tiny room in Gangneung.
It made me happy to know that
my brother lived on in Uncle Tat's mind.
To think that
my brother was undeniably alive…
That brought me a lot of joy back then.
- The three of you, including Sang-yeon?
- We ran into each other near Gwanghwamun.
I feel so left out.
Sounds like you had fun.
What did you talk about?
Nothing much. Mainly about the past
and the Moonee we knew.
Did you drink a lot?
Yeah, a lot. Talking about the past
kept the drinks flowing.
I hope she's doing okay.
Why?
Hope she's not hungover
for her blind date today.
Oh, was that today?
Maybe she'll finally get over
her first love.
First love?
I told you, didn't I?
The guy she met online back in Gangneung.
Right, you did.
I hope her blind date goes well.
If it weren't for the group project,
I would have seen you off at the station.
It's fine. I prefer saying goodbye here.
Goodbyes at the station feel too final.
- I'll write to you.
- You better write me a bunch.
- Take care.
- Okay.
- I'll come visit you.
Go now.
Bye.
Whoa, Kim Sang-hak.
Since when were you smart?
I've always been smart.
Let's take a photo.
Just because you hit on everyone
doesn't mean we all do.
- Have you lost your damn mind?
- Come on, guys!
- Stop it!
- Get over here!
We're so sorry.
- Are you okay?
- Cool it.
Are you okay?
The moment he realized…
that, all along,
Sang-yeon had been there in his past…
I wonder if he still believed her.
Her words that it was Uncle Tat
whom she had liked
and not Kim Sang-hak.
SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING, FRESHMAN
TO CHEON SANG-YEON
UNCLE TAT
I'm glad I'm able to give you this.
Second division, prone firing position!
Prone firing position!
It's getting cold, isn't it?
It's only November,
but it's gotten pretty chilly here too.
Temperatures in Cheorwon, Hwacheon,
and the central mountains of Gangwon
remain below freezing, even now.
In and around Seoul,
daytime highs hover around six…
Now my ears prick up
at the mere mention of "Cheorwon."
- Kim Sang-hak.
- Private Kim Sang-hak!
Thank you, sir!
RYU EUN-JUNG
Everyone knows about
your orange envelopes now.
When the post arrives,
they hand it to me first thing.
I'm at the library because I'm determined
to get a scholarship this semester,
but all I've done this morning
is write this letter.
Yesterday,
I finally met Sang-yeon's blind date.
He is a senior
majoring in computer science at KAIST.
- My date.
- He's pretty cute.
- Hello.
I thought that if all goes well,
we could go on a double date with them,
but I don't think
Sang-yeon's that into him.
Even so, she still goes on dates with him,
but at times, it seems like
she's just going through the motions.
The other day, they went to see a matinee,
but she was back by 4:00 p.m.
What is that?
A VHS player.
Where on earth did you find a VHS player?
What do you mean, where?
I bought it, of course.
If the heavens were to grant me
another chance,
I would tell her that Iove her.
If my love for her must expire,
let it do so after ten thousand years.
Are you crying?
No.
What are you watching?
Stephen Chow.
A Chinese Odyssey.
Is it good?
Yeah.
It was the movie
from Sang-hak oppa's photo.
- Kim Sang-hak.
- Private Kim Sang-hak!
Thank you, sir!
Hey, this one's yours.
Private Kim Beom-jun. Thank you, sir!
Wait. Kim Sang-hak?
Private Kim Sang-hak!
Thank you, sir!
CHEON SANG-YEON
It's from a girl.
This is unfair.
Are you two-timing?
I would never, sir!
She's a girl from my university club!
- From university?
- Yes, sir!
Is she pretty?
Not one bit, sir!
She has a boyfriend, sir!
- Darn it.
- Forget it. Just sit down, man.
Dear Sang-hak seonbae,
I hope you are doing well.
I finally watched
A Chinese Odyssey yesterday.
It was right on top of the shoe cabinet.
I passed the gates just now,
so come down in ten.
Okay.
Thanks, Eun-jung.
I promise to return this favor…
You have a letter
from Sang-hak seonbae.
Oh, you're right.
SENDER
PRIVATE KIM SANG-HAK
Here.
Right, thanks.
He wrote to me
because I asked him for a favor.
Right.
See you.
Are you done?
Hey, about the…
The letter really was
because I asked him for something.
You told me that yesterday.
I just didn't want you to misunderstand.
In what way?
There is no misunderstanding here.
This is Dylan's number.
Her real name is Moon Ji-yeong.
"M."
Every entry is written to her.
But she says
she wants to talk to Sang-hak first.
With him?
Yes.
What's wrong? Is something up?
Weren't you working on photos today
so you can help your mom tomorrow?
I'll get to it.
What's got you in a huff?
God, I'm so pissed!
You broke up because of promise rings?
What's wrong with them?
Another girl helped him pick them out!
Another girl?
There's this chick named Seung-hui,
his friend from middle school.
They both insist they're friends
and 100% platonic,
but I was getting a weird vibe.
So I said, "Let's all meet for drinks."
And guess what?
He served her fishcake soup first!
- Fishcake--
- Look, just hear me out.
I was so pissed that I had a go at him.
That's when he went on about
their platonic relationship,
saying I shouldn't misunderstand.
Their relationship is so platonic
that she chose our promise rings.
Is he out of his damn mind?
Why would he pick out our rings with her?
They've been using the rings as an excuse
to meet and get in touch!
That's…
wrong, isn't it?
What is?
Those two.
What they're doing to you.
Of course it's wrong!
I envy you
for having such clear standards.
Who cares about standards?
It takes two to be in a relationship.
And if I'm upset, he's crossed a line.
I think I'd rather be cheated on.
They're making a fool out of me
with whatever they've got going on.
God, this is so depressing.
Answer your phone.
What?
This is a collect call.
It's me!
Hello?
I'm a private first class now.
Aren't you happy?
Yeah, I'm happy. Why wouldn't I be?
Are you angry?
Why would I be?
You didn't write or come to visit me…
I didn't want to write, so I didn't.
Why didn't you want to?
Why did you send
Sang-yeon's letter to campus?
- What?
- Your letter to Sang-yeon.
Why did you send it to her department?
She says that you wrote to her
because she asked you for a favor.
What exactly was this favor?
Well, you see--
Forget it.
Don't tell me if you don't want to.
It's not like that, just…
Look, Eun-jung.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you about it,
but I really can't discuss it right now.
I promise to tell you soon--
I have no clue what you're getting at.
My question is why you sent it to campus.
Why not our house or the clubroom?
You're just making me question things.
I'm sorry.
Send your letters to our house.
I won't look even if you ask me to.
Hello? Eun-jung?
Hey.
Tough day, I bet.
I'm used to it by now.
Here. Some garae-tteok.
Mom knows you like them, so…
They look so good.
I've actually been craving them.
They're freshly made today.
Also…
Mom wishes you a happy new year.
I should go visit her soon.
I'll put this in the freezer.
Okay.
I never brought the letter up
with Sang-yeon.
They're good.
As if to pretend that…
Have you picked your photos?
…something so trivial
couldn't faze him and me.
- It's been a while.
- Eun-jung, you're here.
Happy new year.
Happy new year to you too.
And this.
Sorry it took so long.
It's no biggie. This wasn't urgent anyway.
I'm still sorry.
Could I also have some photo paper?
Ilford 11 by 14, glossy, please.
Ilford 11 by 14, glossy.
You must be preparing for an exhibition.
Yes, it opens on February 13th. Will you
not come since Sang-hak won't be there?
I will if I can make time.
Is your friend also participating?
Cheon Sang-yeon, was it?
How do you know her?
Right, you three had drinks together.
Take me with you next time.
She's a really close childhood friend.
You've always been friends,
not just through the club?
Yes, since elementary school.
Wow. What an uncanny coincidence.
I guess.
Eun-jung, guess what?
You would never have met Sang-hak
if it weren't for her.
Sorry?
If it weren't for her, Sang-hak would
never have gotten into your university.
Some time ago, she messaged Sang-hak
on her brother's behalf,
which helped Sang-hak
get his act together.
A message?
Yes, a message to say
that her brother was doing well.
At the time,
we all thought that Moonee had sent it.
Sang-hak mentioned seeing Moonee online.
I do have a crush.
Someone I met in an online chat room
while I was in Gangneung.
"Online chat room"?
It wasn't mutual.
Do you know what he looks like?
Yes.
I followed him around.
What exhibition was this?
Oh, this.
It was with a club I was in
during my gap year.
Why?
Oh, it's nothing.
I thought it might be someone I know.
I do have a crush.
It wasn't mutual.
I followed him around.
What are you doing in here?
I was looking at this photo.
Do you like him?
Do you like Sang-hak?
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi